all right we're gonna meditate so please
get ready to meditate
yesterday we had a nice class with all
the volunteers I don't know if you saw
the poster outside but there's about 200
volunteers here working very very hard
and I'd like to give them a hand
what was the subject yesterday did you
guys forget last night impossible
we're talking about impossible like when
you have a fight with your husband in
the kitchen that husband is impossible
you know pain is coming from me
because I have a seed in my mind for
Penn dog doesn't have okay
seed makes you dog or humans okay so I
have Penn seed in my mind who put the
Penn Stater
only you can put you cannot give seed to
other person not possible how to put the
panting give him to other person okay
and when you see your hand open it puts
a seed in your mind okay
now yesterday we had three questions in
the Heart Sutra class so we had a heart
sutra class with my friends Ebola Ebola
son today but it's all right okay
and I asked three questions they know
the answer so you guys cannot answer
other people okay three questions number
one do I have pen in my head
yes is there a pen in my head yeah is
there pen in my hand which come from me
because I gave Katherine pen okay now
difficult question is there a pen in my
hand which come from the pin no what's
the name of that conky okay
consume now interesting therefore the
person who really understand coaching
they love to give thing to other people
okay that's it's time this person
understand coaching they're polite they
smile and they get things to everybody
because they understand culture okay
cool all right so this morning we're
gonna do lion stance meditation
I talked to Aldo Andrea they told me how
far they went how far in the meditation
and we will go further okay
and we're going to go through the eight
steps we will go up the elevator and
then we will go to the ninth floor and
we will meditate about our teacher okay
then that teacher is any teacher in your
life okay who's your first grade teacher
your mom okay and your father okay then
you have school teacher then you have a
work teacher then you have your wife
teacher late later you have your kids
teacher okay maybe you have spiritual
teachers okay but in this meditation we
will ask three questions number one is
there teacher in your mouth yeah number
two is there teacher in your mind which
come from your seat
yeah number three is there teacher in
your mind does not come from your seat
no impossible
what is that that's a teacher a message
from teacher you're gonna wake these
guys out not me okay so there's no
teacher in my mind which doesn't come
from me okay
and that's coaching now I said if you're
a good person if you understand coaching
you will give things to other people
okay if you don't understand coaching
you will not give things to other people
okay if you understand coaching you
respect the teacher which come from you
okay if you don't understand console
you don't respect teacher and then you
don't make seed for teacher and then
teacher goes away or something
okay okay so in the meditation you all
of your teacher parents school teacher
person who taught you your work then we
will respect them make new seat then the
teacher will stay with us okay okay cool
okay let's start okay clear we are
meditating in a group so please be
careful try to be quiet and we're gonna
let take a little bit long this morning
okay so be comfortable
usually in the meditation we start by
watching the breath but here we will
start by watching the air-conditioner so
put your mind on the sound of the
air-conditioning
don't forget this special breathing for
meditation when you breathe out and you
reach the end of the breath then push
out a little bit more air and then you
will never get nervous during the
meditation ok listen to the
air-conditioner
then please come to the heart
watch the beating of the heart we are
not inside the heart yet we are watching
the beating into her
now go inside the heart and the hardest
beating around us inside the heart is
not dark and wet place it's a very
beautiful room lots of sunlight
remember to do the breathing extra
exhale
now we go to the center of the heart and
beating sound seems far away
now let's put our mind into a single
sugar crystal
from the outside it looks very small but
when we put the mind into it it's a very
comfortable meditation room with lots of
Sun right
now I've made my mind as large as the
Pacific Ocean stretching across this
whole world peaceful deep
remember to do the extra exhale
now we had the Bliss guy my mind
stretches from the bottom of the ocean
to the top of the sky
you know we decide to turn them my not
like turning off a light in my room if a
thought comes up then block it
remember the extra exhale
and now the mind if the mind thinks of
thoughts or it may just just let them
move through the mind and go away don't
don't fight with the mind
now we're ready to start the meditation
then please choose one of your teachers
in your diet maybe it's your mom or your
dad or a school teacher or Dharma
teacher and ask them in a happy way to
come and meditate with you and they come
they're very happy they're not a picture
they are a real person they are
breathing they're looking at you with a
lot of love and a big smile because you
are meditating and they know it's going
to help you
so bring the teacher to sit with you
then think something about this teacher
that you really love something quality
they have like patience or working hard
for other people
then the teachers like the pen and the
good thing I see in them is coming from
me so I must have made a seed for that
in my past life the first law of karma
says that the seed is similar to the
result if my teacher is very patient I
must have been very patient in my past
life if my teacher is very helpful to
other people
I must have been very helpful to people
in my past
so let's go on a trip to our past night
and just imagine where did I knit like
hundreds of years ago what was my job
what did I look like man or woman what
was my family line and what did I do
that I see this beautiful thing in my
teacher so you are free in the
meditation make a beautiful story
don't be afraid to make a movie and you
are the good hero in the movie okay
we're gonna spend a little bit of time
here enjoy sometimes you will get
distracted you will think about lunch
then slowly come back to the meditation
okay a woman so
now please come back to your teacher and
again enjoy this beautiful quality in
them you can ask those same three
questions number one does my teacher had
this beautiful quality
number two
does this beautiful quality come from me
number three does this beautiful colony
come from itself
and the answer is no and that's conky
if my teacher has consumed then I can
keep the teacher in my line
when I go home from Thailand if I share
with other people
who are interested gently then I will
plant the seeds to see my teachers stay
with me
now let's go back down we respectfully
tell the teacher we are going to come
out of the meditation and we come down
to the eighth level the mind is having
thoughts and pictures but I ignored them
I am super quiet and the mind is talking
maybe but I don't listen to it
remember to do the extra exhale
now I go to never selling it
if the mind is thinking thoughts I block
them to keep the mind quiet
now I bring my mind back to the sea and
the sky
now to the ocean alone very deep
no very gently into the sugar crystal
very tiny remember the extra exhale
and now to the center of the heart the
heartbeat sounds far away
now to the inside of the heart and the
walls are beating close to me
and now come back to your body and watch
your heart
then watch three long exhales to close
them in attainment
and then open your eyes
Degas judge okay we are an easy place to
find it timís Emma TSE our ma TS CR MA
okay in the text and Nick will help you
okay Semillon ik t s er ma la s TS e r
ma la yes okay good so this is a new
item and it's a new principle it's
called an ear legged Pumbaa saying your
name you promote your your Jing language
sound like my Chinese language they
teach me Chinese language you know like
- on how then I say to my Chinese fan
- Aang how then they look at me like
this oh you speak Thai then she's the
same in in the Jing language okay when
we are born okay we get body and their
mind it's like you go to the you land in
the airport and you go to rent a car you
you pay and you get a car and it's the
same thing when you're born you get a
rental car
why didn't I say you buy a car
yeah perfect
$0 yeah you have to give it back okay so
it's temporary rental okay we get this
body then this body gets called right
now it gets too hard
and this body gets hungry okay I have a
friend she said I will never eat animal
then she got very very hungry and all
her friends were eating some fish and
she also eat the fish she decided to be
vegetarian but she got very hungry and
there's no other food so she finally she
ate the fish so when you rent this car
you will do bad things to take care of
this car because this car is not very
good car this car needs food every day
two three times
this card needs a sweater okay then this
car needs many things okay then you know
of course everybody in this room is a
nice person nobody will steal anything
here there's very few places in the
world where there's 500 people and you
can leave your purse here no one will
take it
there are Buddhist people but if they
really need money
their mother think their kids are
starving they will take it everybody me
also we are same okay so we have this
rental car then we try to be good person
we try not to hurt other people but if
we have no food we will still okay this
is human being
okay so we will still to feed the body
then from this kind of life we will get
another rental car next time but that
rental car also beat this kind this is
not Tesla this is some old American car
okay it needs a lot of it's always
breaking it needs a sweater
it needs a food you know it needs many
thing poopoo it's not a very good car
okay
inside blood and meat and there are
5,000 important parts in your body and
they are not cooperating
they are not yeah the lungs are fighting
against the heart the lung wants more
cool
the heart needs more warm then they are
fighting each other if the lungs win we
get caught if the heart wins we have
trouble to breathe so 5,000 parts are
fighting with each other I translated
for a great traditional doctor for
several years and they said interesting
thing when the lungs and the heart are
in balance this is unusual healthy
person is not normal okay
sick person is normal healthy is
temporary so to get food even good
people if there's no food in this hotel
if there's no food in this
we were still food okay to to stay alive
in the war everyone will do bad things
then when we die because of stealing the
food we will get this kind of body next
one way this body is very lucky we have
rental car but it's not very good
quality okay why we did bad things to
get this bunny okay so now listen this
is what we reach this part we got body
like this we must eat we must work and
if we don't get food we will still if we
still next time we will get this kind of
body body steel steel body body steel
steel body and it's a Soaker okay this
is samsara this is the proof of samsara
okay so we have to get out of this body
we have to change it and if you see come
see me directly then from the inside the
body will start to change okay and then
later you won't have body like this body
and doesn't need food and it won't hurt
people to get food then stay forever
that body is very cool that body is very
cool if you have it you can help people
in many cities at the same time okay
very efficient body it's a real Tesla
Model X Bunny and the rental is
permanent okay you never have to give it
back so right now we we are in a pretty
lousy body and we have to change it okay
we have to change it don't wait until
it's time to go back to the airport
okay well you are young see coaching
okay
the working and other things in your
life it's not emergency to change the
body its emergency we have to do it now
and the best way is conscious okay
that's why we spend so much time on
Kangxi okay let's go little I know
you're need a pee-pee break what did my
teacher say I don't care okay let's go a
little bit more okay here we go
Pumbaa de la Lumia Daniel Mundi ningún
and ten shots but I'm gonna move to
Pumbaa D okay make pooh-bah Phu and GP
or possibility I put what they do not on
your monkey Ning ending ten chopper your
bed do taking dunya because this body
was made by bad since we will always
have problem it will always get sick it
will always get hungry it always want to
poop okay that's a not very good bunny
day your chin chainsaw Daniel Tata maybe
a couple red chilly are Maya yeah I'm
gonna so getting a mom okay by chaining
to take it doing anything yeah even if
you don't have disease right now maybe
there's one inside we don't know maybe
we already have cancer it didn't come
out yet we have a friend she got cancer
I think she's dying No
and we are all surprised you know oh you
were in the class last month and you you
look fine
yeah but I didn't know I have cancer you
know it's growing inside okay so this
body is even if you feel pretty good
right now
don't worry you will feel bad later this
is a nature of this body so we have to
change it now okay angelic ever done
teaching eating a Shinigami
hey man demon came I didn't know give me
a like you watch him eating a key Nathan
Kancha pitcher so this body came from
bad karma and to keep it alive we do
Beckham and it's a circle from Edina
Daniel Cunningham but take ownership and
run or never knew Mindy so then we are
in samsara cetera has two causes and now
our class will go to these two causes
we will talk about these two causes okay
number one is bad seed okay
bad seed which make this body like pin
this one and this one say okay this one
also come from me
this one also come from me okay so what
makes this lousy body two things okay my
my bad karma in in the past maybe I ate
meat in my past life then because of me
they kill then okay something very bad
in China right now conditi okay
they killed ten billion chickens in
China every year
okay ten billion and each one has a body
they also want to be alive like us so
when you go to Conda G eat french fry
eat the salad don't eat people
okay they found out now scientists say
meat has poison inside we call it color
when you get too much fat in your blood
cholesterol okay the main source of
cholesterol is meat and 65 percent of
American people
they eat they eat them in okay and they
get cholesterol and 400,000 die every
year from Candida okay and similar food
okay so don't eat it
you can make cringing it makes you
healthy okay
all my friends I think I became
vegetarian 40 years ago then my friends
told me you will not have protein you
will get sick you you you won't be
healthy
okay you don't need me okay
you don't mean it it just cause trouble
for other people it's okay all right so
two things cause this body karma
what cause karma Lele dictum that's okay
Denise unbuttoned it a somebody kill a
you know dated lewd and luckily very
famous kosher fourth chapter let's do it
together
okay say Lele Jatin not so okay all the
stars you see in the sky come from comma
teeny Simba what is come there's a raw
karma okay most basic comer okay when
you think it's coming you're right now
we are making many comments
I have two people why guess who I talk
so slow then I made three commas in in
three seconds
senpai Yuki Leonor very famous thinking
is most basic kind of karma telltale do
the knocking lay and then secondary
karma what you say and what you do okay
so those are those cause this body karma
what we say and what we do and what we
say and what we do is caused by what we
think so thinking comes one second
before talking and one second before we
do something we will think something
oh it's too cold I have to tell Jasmine
then when you see Jasmine you will do
body camera ready
okay let's body comma then we'll say
something
oh this she said do you enjoy the class
yeah everything happy this class very
good for Eskimo people if Eskimo come
they will enjoy the class okay then
thinking come just before then comes
talking and do something eskimo like
this okay so the mother karma is
thinking so if we want to understand who
made this body how we made this button
we need to understand that thinking
karma okay
so we're going to spend the next two or
three weeks we are going to study
thinking Karma how can we improve it and
then it will change the body
okay we're gonna take a break now so AJ
we're gonna do that after the break okay
we'll take fifteen minute break go get
some exercise to stay warm see you in 15
minutes okay as I said before I've been
teaching this lamrim for I think eight
years and it's good for you if you can
hear a little bit from the past eight
years so I'm doing review with pictures
and usually I will do in the evening but
this evening we have another jump we
will have a special fire okay and also
we will have three marriages
yeah then what's the purpose of the fire
it has two meanings
number one we burn up our or bad karma
okay so during the fire we put karma in
the fire offering and we throw it in the
fire and it burns the old bad karma okay
if you if you want to you can write if
you did some big bad thing in your life
and all of us did okay
I also did if I tell you what I did when
I was young you will run away okay so
write it down on a paper and at the end
of the fire we will throw the paper in
the fire and during the fire we will
have three fires and some very
experienced teachers
some of them who did three years silent
retreat
we have several teachers here who did
three years silent retreat no one is
chin Zone one is Earl what is Gayle say
okay
one is gushing Michael I think that's
everybody so you know they will help us
with the fire and then you are very
welcome to you will also put something
in the fire okay so we will give you a
plate
and you put you take it and you put in
the fire okay don't go like this
okay little bit elegant okay don't go
like this okay it's a okay
you can practice okay not like this okay
and they will help you okay with style
like Jamie very handsome okay like that
okay all right good
and then think about it I throw my bag
comer and burn it that's the first
meaning of the offering then Buddha says
love it when you confess your bad deeds
okay okay so never be afraid to tell
your teacher
the worst thing you did okay they're
happy that you are on earth and when you
can clean that seed if you talk about it
so throw the fire then you know I did a
bad thing when I was young
long time ago and also yesterday be
honest okay and then burn it then the
Buddhist love the smell of this truth it
makes them very happy it's good to tell
the teacher the good thing you did it's
also good to tell the teacher the bad
thing you did that smoke is very sweet
for them then we will improve slowly
okay it takes time to become good person
okay we are bad person for 10 million
years it's not going to change in one
year or two years okay slow small
progress and many big mistakes even even
now okay so don't get depressed okay
don't say I'm bad person it's true but
you are improving that's good and that's
smoke it goes up to the Buddha the smoke
goes to the Buddhist
and they mmm somebody burning their bag
smells okay and then that smoke slowly
will reach the whole room and it will
bring peace to other people 500 people
in time and they are burning their bad
seats and that smoke will touch the
world the wind will carry everywhere
right it will make people feel happy
okay so those two purposes of the fart
number one burner number two peace then
if you're tired you don't have to stay
it takes about two and a half three
hours so if you feel okay that's enough
for me then go home sleep happy okay you
don't have to stay till the last minute
okay then we will have refreshments have
fun okay life is very short life is very
difficult if you're in Thailand you
should enjoy it during the fire
okay then that's Buddha likes you to be
happy
the purpose of Buddhism is to be happy
so while you are doing Buddhism you're
supposed to have fun okay okay I guess I
stayed for one hour
I enjoy the fire now I want to go home
and watch TV and sleep okay again don't
be this kind of Buddhist okay okay fun
song okay one one five Nick we're gonna
review the old Norman
because we we don't have time tonight
that's a different one that's a
different one that's the correct one but
can you just show one thing no there so
I'm reviewing the part where they talk
about how to study this subject and in
the picture there's a person having
coffee with their face and that's a part
of this program okay so go to the class
listen to the class then after the class
enjoy have coffee have some tea
the pastries are very good in the class
I drink I drink the green tea after the
class I eat the pastry okay go there
enjoy have nice tea and talk about what
you heard in the class
three times this is tradition okay with
your friends publish is checking Jamie's
knowledgebase what did you doing what
did you hear from the class
guess not talk about the body then he'd
talk about rental car what he's saying
I don't remember then take three or four
friends why one of them was a I was
asleep during that part then your friend
will tell you what guess I said about
rental car then said did you enjoy
Jaime's presentation oh I was asleep
during that part then review with your
friend okay this is a old tradition 2000
years okay go have tea go have coffee
bye pastry don't tell anybody
eat and talk about the class okay
there's a most fun okay it's very very
important for remember later okay so
this is tradition
okay next picture mr. mink yeah this is
called how to think about yourself okay
then you can think it's called think you
are sick person okay think you have
sickness like inside spiritual cancer
then think about this teaching it's like
medicine for you
okay then the teacher is all of the
teachers are like doctor okay we are
then all the teachers together or we are
like medical staff and teaching it's
like a medicine okay so maybe our body
is not sick but our hardest thing all
the time
so when you come here you said I'm
taking medicine your friends ask you are
you taking medicine yes
what kind I'm in I'm taking two three
times a day to fix my mind since my
hands okay so this tradition to think I
have to come to the class
I'm getting medicine and there's a
doctor there's a gala he's the small
doctor Buddha is the director of the
hospital then I'm working for the Buddha
okay
people ask me why Jasmine gave the
teachers this white coat this is a
doctor's coat understand okay next one
this is a opera okay then in the Opera
they will tell the story of the famous
person went on 17 years war to India you
know with the pig with The Monkey King
you know they will tell the story of the
famous people
then some people will come to my teacher
wait don't take away my picture yeah and
they will say you want to go to the here
the Opera he said why or they will
invite him to go to India you want to
see Deer Park why this is a Buddha's
first time then my teachers are funny
like no you don't want to go to do
parents know you don't want to go to
upper no I don't want to hear about
Swensen I want to be something okay
understand I don't want to go to the
Deer Park and see where Buddha step
there 2,000 years ago I want to stay
here study Lamia I want to become Buddha
then they will think about me okay so
this alarm traditions okay they will
come to Thailand there will be statue
here of Nick people say all 500 years
ago
Nick taught and the gardener here you
know and they will do a Gore walk around
Nick statute really gender okay so it's
good to respect all the holy places
that's good and it's good to read the
story of the famous Saints like the
gardener and do it sometimes but spend
most of your time on your practice you
become better and let them make your
statue
and let them sing shall be study in the
tile and study in the tires and she
taught vinaya you know let them tell
your story okay so work on yourself
it got a holy place sometimes but make
your house holy place people will come
to your house five hundred years from
now
oh she was normal person then she
studied lions dance then she start
coming on that day her body start to
change and then she became Buddha in
this house the people can walk around
your house
okay I don't spend all the time think
about the old Buddhist okay you are the
next Buddha and they will walk around
your house for blessing okay and it's
true okay so get ready maybe you can
charge money to work on just kidding
okay next one
Nick 118 good yeah this a picture is
supposed to remind you when you are
sitting with your friends in the coffee
shop you can play picture game show the
picture that guy is singing they'd say
what's the meaning oh this they're gonna
write a song about me after I become
Buddha
okay wait where you guys going
what injection you don't have
oh I'm sure Tim gonna give you this
afternoon right second part of the items
okay they will give you okay it's not
Tim's fault its geshe-la phone case I'm
too busy but no they want the printed to
add to their book okay so you guys try
to finish by afternoon okay then we'll
get ready for you right now you can take
in your phone with your father
okay come on
I need the picture of the shark don't
forget it's your thing okay there's a
problem in the world now this you know
100 years ago they don't have penicillin
so we cannot do operation on people they
will die they the infection and then I
don't know then they discovered
penicillin and if you put it if you do
operation then you put penicillin that
you won't get infection and you won't
die if you don't have penicillin you
will you possibly you will die so now
there's a problem in the world
some people become resistant to
penicillin those germs they learn to
fight the penicillin and so for some
people penicillin doesn't working out
their germs and their body adapted and
now when you give them penicillin it
doesn't work okay why are we talking
about that the purpose of this class is
to fight the negative thought in your
own heart
okay and we are going to start a long
list of negative there's 84,000 it's
very depressing anger jealousy then long
long list
okay then the purpose of coming to
Thailand is to learn conscience function
is the main gun to fight those 84,000
you know if your husband yell are you
then
you remember the pin and and you say
okay come from me and then you change
your scene
don't yell at your kid okay don't make
seed for yelling now I've been teaching
for out of 40 years and some of my
student with me for 25 years
you know then recently someone came to
me you know guess not
I have trouble with my husband I'm
having trouble with my husband do you
have suggestions then they said and
don't tell me about the C's I heard this
theme you know many years don't tell me
about the same I need something new
they got resistant to the penicillin
understand okay then I was the disturbed
you know I've confused you know you want
me to help you but you don't want me to
tell you the husband come from you
yeah yes I tell me something new I
couldn't think of anything okay
I'm sorry that's all I give you a
nuclear weapon
and you don't use it and you want a
slingshot I don't sell slingshots
I only sell nuclear weapons okay I
cannot teach you some small thing you go
by a book in the airport how to be happy
with the husband the husband who come
from the husband you can find a book in
the airport about how to fix the husband
who come from the husband like talk to
him for whole night tell him not to yell
are you okay then I don't I don't sell
that I sell penicillin okay then don't
get used to it
if you come here three four times and
you don't use it when you go home you
will stop to listen about it you
okay you you won't hear it the third
time fourth time you won't hear when I
think my really old student okay when I
hold up the pen immediately fall asleep
okay so at home if you have trouble to
sleep ask your friend to bring your pen
okay so the first time you hear use it
okay if you hear it three times and
you're doing you say you will you won't
hear it anymore cool is it you think no
don't keep coming to Thailand don't take
it now you taught the pen last year why
are you teaching the pen again because
you still fighting with your husband
okay okay I understand if you stop
fighting with your husband I will stop
teaching the pen okay I agree okay all
right all right
next picture this is John Brady when he
was the arm
hundred years ago if you look carefully
he still has some here what's he doing
in this picture you can see the date
he's talking in 2007 at a conference 11
years ago
he's fundraising for his China look he
said please give me money we have to
save the hobo ok why are we talking
about that after you study Dharma you
have responsibility to help keep it
alive sometimes you can see a map of all
the religions of the world and Buddhism
almost died ok those books are almost
gone I went to the airport in Shenton
they are selling a small chinjung in
this man chanting this big and and I
went to study shoe fire in Canada from
master Shiva
then he said what do you want to learn
first you know I said can I do hinging
he said yeah my family changing experts
and we are doing for 15 generations we
are doing hinging then he taught me the
first few characters and then I said by
the way what's the meaning of this
character I don't know your family's
enjoying too far for 15 generations but
we don't know what's a minute okay so
don't don't do like that okay keep the
book alive in the world and keep the
meaning alive in the world these are we
have to keep both okay well I see I pick
and keep the book aligned but you have
to keep the meaning in life okay this is
your job okay then you have to help how
to repay the kindness of a Buddha make
sure the book doesn't disappear
okay each generation has responsibility
we have to keep the book for the and
give to the next generation and this is
your responsibility if you after you
come here once after you heard this
Dharma if you heard that to husband's in
the kitchen then after that you have
responsibility to give the book to the
next generation and explain to the next
generation okay my my job is finished in
two days then your job begins you are
the next generation okay then your work
will start your work will begin okay
that's your job each each generation
have to give to the next generation
otherwise it will die okay next one this
kid he has a cold he's sick and he's
taking medicine looks a little bit like
cutie actually
anatoly savchenko so he's taking the
medicine but he's also sitting in the
lamrim class $400 not 400 for $100 if
someone can guess what is this okay go
ahead
she will repeat you can just say that's
true but that's not this picture not not
I mean look at that it's it's called
taking as I listened
you can do both okay I'll tell you the
meaning okay in the class use them
anything okay in the class use the
medicine okay don't wait until you go
home you can start to take the medicine
in the class okay you are sitting next
to somebody or you feel cold in the
class gets less teaching function
there's not teaching the pen but you are
feeling uncomfortable by the way we
turned off the air okay but this morning
I'm also called then while I'm teaching
Kong Xin can come from you like why did
Tim make so cold
what's forward to what happened I am NOT
taking the medicine during the class
understand okay it's very deep meaning
you take the medicine immediately don't
walk around for two days with the
medicine guess that's giving you
medicine I don't put in your pocket I
will use it when I get home okay use it
in the class Tim okay this is not done
oh oh come from me understand who made
the room called this money you did okay
take the medicine during the class no
geshe-la I saw him with turning the
air-conditioning on who made Tim okay
understand
did Tim turn on the air conditioning to
Highness money yes but who made him you
when did you hear that in the class this
morning so use the medicine immediately
even during the class get lost
teaching about the fire we're gonna burn
our bad comer didn't start right now
ready
okay start it right on a paper right now
don't think I will use it I will do it
when I get home okay when I'm eating
lunch do it during the class okay
this means take the medicine immediately
it's a tradition in London because you
will be too busy you're going to airport
you packing you will forget start start
practice now don't say good luck I'd
give my practice tomorrow morning know
do your practice on this chair now okay
don't wait up tomorrow okay good that's
a cuties picture meaning okay next one
this is not Nick singing rock and roll
tomorrow which I think he's gonna do
this is a talk about the motivation for
becoming a teacher
okay so we have in this room I don't
know 20 teachers
they worked very hard okay they studied
for 20 years 15 years but they started
like you okay they came to lamb rim
thirty years ago my teachers love him
and they listen and they practice and
they become teacher okay so it's a great
honor and it's very important that you
guys become teachers that's very
important you should do it it's my dream
you become teachers in fact
say gee I'll be ready after this in him
okay
so this is about when you become teacher
there's three things you have to be
careful
number one is money people offer you
money it's very good to offer to make
often to teacher it's very good
money's helpful we need money to pay for
the airplanes and things like that but
it's not the most important thing okay
what the teacher wants from you is your
practice right now you feel cold and if
I see you're like this you're like this
you're looking over that way where's Tim
then if you go like this
then I teacher feel happy oh you are you
are learning in the class we call the
offering of your practice okay it's the
best offering what I feel happy if you
give money out there after this class I
appreciate but if you come to me next
year in Bali and you say guess not
since I came to the lamrim my husband
and me fighting much less okay I don't
expect every day perfect it's not gonna
happen okay
ten million years you are fighting okay
you're not gonna change in one year okay
don't expect that you will get depressed
okay don't expect that Michael study his
whole life every day he makes mistakes
okay let's be honest okay but if you
come to me next year
and you say our marriage is improving we
used to fight every day now one day a
week we don't fight then I'm like hey
tompa yea you're improving okay then
that's the best offering to the teacher
okay so when you become teacher don't
think too much about the money okay we
can teach in the shim Bakar it's okay we
don't need a big hotel in Thailand okay
if we don't have money we can I taught
for many years in my car okay okay
second thing don't expect anyone respect
you okay in the class they will say okay
I love you then they will give you big
trouble okay student is like kids okay
we love them and there are a lot of
trouble okay so student will give you
trouble then teacher
mom cannot sorry the boss of the company
can fire the bad worker
but the mom cannot fire the kids
you fired going cannot do it's a
lifetime job these senior guys they know
that the kids some of them don't grow up
after 60 years but you cannot fire them
right
you have to student also after you start
to teach the student in this tradition
you cannot fire them okay so they
respect you like this then they give you
trouble whole day
that's teachers job okay so don't expect
- in Michael's life is rock and roll
star everybody's nice to get you know
it's not like that okay mom's job is
very difficult never sleeps always
worried you know that's the same as a
teacher okay so don't think I'm you're
gonna get very famous oh okay don't
expect that it's a lot of work but mom
knows it's the sweetest job in the world
it's the best job in the world okay mom
jobs best job in the world
people ask me you know
I'm think - I'm thinking to teach you
know what's your advice I think number
one it's the hardest job in the world
number two I did it my whole life
it's the happiest life you can have okay
there's nothing happier okay number one
most difficult job most trouble kids are
trouble students are more trouble
but there's no better jump okay I did it
my whole life
I'm extremely happy I'm still have
trouble to fundraise and it's trouble
for me at night I cannot sleep you know
oh we don't have money but people ask me
are you happy yeah this is the best job
in the world
happiest job in the world okay that the
motivation must be pure motivation must
be killed okay don't expect you're going
to get famous don't expect people are
gonna give you money don't expect
respect okay ninety percent you will get
trouble
from this okay and be happy it's worth
it
okay there's no better jump all right
in m12 - I taught you this one already
oh that's a storage facility behind you
can see the big white building the
college is one of the red buildings and
so I want to buy that okay adam-12 to
show the picture don't show the words
adam-12 - okay I taught it to you
already if you have one too - yeah how
did dollars I taught you already try
okay go ahead
she can say nope
you are close but this lady there will
be angels in every country at the
Auckland it tortures not exact come on I
tell you this one on it what's the
subject we are talking about
I like it if you teach even to your
family in the kitchen all the buddhas
will come and they will check teach
pretty good she's teaching the pen
pretty good okay so when you teach
Buddha's will come you smell sweet
they are like bees you are like honey
okay understand okay so make them happy
when you get home teach a pen okay to
your family to your friends especially
if your friend is fighting with the
husband okay
teach them where the husband come from
okay then of course they will improve
but more important Buddhist will come
because they like to hear someone teach
the pen
my old students when I teach the pen
they fall asleep but I don't mind while
they are sleeping all the Buddhists come
to listen so I feel pretty happy okay I
need a couple microphones we're gonna do
some question and answer me okay guys
yeah she does get 100 okay okay Stokes
$2.00 yeah
Pomona mo savonia Vietnam we booted up
bearded Smoochum set at Yankee Ladner
okay I told her she has to take her
husband to dinner with $100 okay he say
okay all right questions any question
any something you did he he will decide
huh
they're due to us to see it
any person wouldn't buy this also
teaching even sutras tell me master stay
away from those misbehavior friends good
question
there's two kinds of friends we call
dick dog and chill dog - dog person they
will come to your house
let's go to coffee shop why let's review
the Longmen from Thailand just enjoy you
know we will have coffee we will have
pastry and we will enjoy together then
we call shadow dharma friend don't waste
your time
then dig dog they are sitting in the
same room I've forget it you know let's
go see movie you know there's a
spider-man movie
let's go see Jen Leung are okay
you know let's go see this movie I went
to see it's pretty cool
in Shanghai thing guangzhou yeah so at
that moment you have choice there's two
friends in the room one asked you
let's go review lamrim in the shim baka
then the other fan same now come on
let's go see movie okay at that moment
the second friend
it's like dimmer okay then to the second
fan you should say thank you I like a
movie maybe we can go tomorrow guess
that said we're supposed to relax
sometimes guess I also went to see Jen
long are okay but today I'm supposed to
review then is the second person Buddha
or not yes why they're testing you they
are testing you okay they're checking
are you good student or not
so this week a Buddha will come to as
your husband and he will yell are you he
want to check if you learned anything in
Thailand okay he want to remind you
about function so don't think all the
Buddhists are very nice and you learn
more from trouble than you learn from no
trouble okay the person who give you
trouble is teaching you a lot when we
don't have trouble we don't remember
conscious when we do have trouble we
remember now
maybe those troublemaker is the Buddha
and maybe they are not Buddha actually
we don't know okay could be Buddha could
not be Buddha but it's more help to us
if we think Buddha
okay so be honest if the Buddhist is
this husband yelling in see Buddha guess
not I don't know is it possible yeah
it's possible if their Buddha will they
yell at you so you can think about
conceive possible
that's enough that's logical
okay you don't have to say my husband
definitely but I guess I said so it's
true but in our level at our level we
can say honestly could be Buddha now if
it's Buddha and you disrespect then you
make a really bad comment okay I'll tell
you a story so I was in the diamond
business for 19 years you know and in
the beginning with in the beginning the
company cannot pay me salary I work for
free we don't have any money sometimes
we cannot do payday to payday cannot pay
their salary
then they will come to me can you take
the salary next week can you that's it
okay it's okay we don't have money I
said okay you can give me next week
sometimes six weeks they cannot pay me
later we became largest diamond jewelry
company in the world then the pay is
unbelievable then I will give half of my
money directly to the monastery no tax
and legal they will take half my sari
gifted me then so every six month I have
to go to my boss you know and I would
say you know you owe me $100,000 or
$200,000
then you have to give now today you have
to give to the monastery they would say
well how much is it I would say two
hundred thousand then he was saying
let's make three hundred he will give me
st 100,000 that I like cool thank you he
said for your monastery yeah I'm saying
cool and he did for I don't know many
years did finally one day he gave me a
huge amount extra today I said can I ask
you personal questions yeah go ahead
he's from Israel he's Jewish
dude they are all Jewish then I said you
are from your Israel person yeah you are
all Israel people it's tough Jewish
people yeah sister why you give extra
money to Buddhist monastery every time
you give big mount to the monastery why
you do that
he said you never know which religion is
correct
okay
possible Jewish is correct possible
Christian is credit possible Muslim
escape possible your monasteries correct
so intelligent persons give to everybody
you know
then after die you can go good place
he's like very funny you know we are the
same you know the people who yell at you
people who give you trouble
we don't know who better to be respect
to each person okay maybe this brother
may be disbursed we don't know
then his donation too many religion some
must be wrong right but it's not a
problem to respect the person who's not
a Buddha is also not a problem to
respect a person and find out later they
are not Buddha it still you make a good
scene
so respect everybody it's more safe
more safe okay okay
- no coefficient or the witness will
come to see us any or so yeah good good
question this is second chapter I'm the
gardener that chapter is called going
and coming and if Buddha come from me
why I have to ask them to come okay so
when the Buddha comes it come from you
okay so there's two coming okay Buddhist
coming but Buddha come from you I'll
give you an example so I live in a small
town
it's called rim rock very small town
in China New York is a small town okay
it's true but my town is super small I
think we have three thousand people in
my tournament and we have post office
and there's two ladies work there yeah I
think there are 90 years old then you
you write a letter you give to them
there's a bell you have to ring the bell
I think they are sleeping in the bank
and you've got B then they come out they
take a letter and they mail the letter
okay it takes 15 minutes for me to walk
to the post office if I write a letter
to get in Michaels
and I take it to the old lady and I've
dressed to myself it will take two weeks
to come to my house I can walk there 15
minutes so let's say I send I write a
letter to get in my car you know you are
really stupid your phantom then I put in
the give to the old lady then after two
weeks the post of the postman will come
I think he's the son of the old lady
he's also then he would give me the then
I will open it up it says get last
phantom then I question for you
should I get angry at the postman who
brought me the letter no he didn't write
the letter he just delivered the learned
okay your husband is the postman you
wrote the letter he just delivered you
the letters when your husband fight with
you he's delivering you your own scene
if the husband criticizes you who wrote
the letter you did okay then don't kill
the postman okay he didn't do anything
he just deliver you your own letter when
your husband criticizes he's just
postman okay he didn't write the letter
you wrote the letter understand now wife
gets not talking about that some people
ask me okay
for example when I take a husband I have
a headache and I take a aspirin does it
work or not sometimes if you helped
other people with the headache in the
past if you planted the seed to have the
medicine work
then the medicine will work for you okay
if you ignored your friends who have
headache then when you take the Aspen it
will not work okay
Yoga is the same some people take yoga
class get stung like Anatol okay
some people take the same class they get
hurt okay it's not the class is the
postman the aspen is the postman okay
they didn't write the letter
okay understand so when you're in the
shim barker and you are teaching you pan
to your friends and the buddhists come
to you and the buddhists come to you did
the buddhist come to you don't forget
the three questions number one do i have
pen in my hand yeah number two what's
number two
do I have pen in my hand which come from
me
yeah number three do I have pen in my
hand which come from pen no when you
taste a pen in the Shema car will the
Buddha come yeah
question number two will they come
because of your seat yes will any Buddha
come to the Shem become when you are
explaining the pen who doesn't come from
okay
but did the Buddha come yeah okay so
don't forget the three questions always
ask the three questions then you won't
get confused is there pen in my head is
there a pen in my hand come from me is
there pen a hand come from pen no is
there Buddha come to the coffee shop
without your seat no impossible okay
yesterday we study in the gardener all
of the volunteers and we the subject is
the eight impossible okay it means
cannot happen didn't not come from you
okay cool one more question
because our sis create so we created our
system to become
yeah good good
okay so I wasn't born as a Buddhist you
know I was born Christian and my mom we
have four brothers and my mom take us to
the church you know and I enjoy the
church and it was very nice
I still go sometimes to my same church
when I was a kid I know the smell I like
a feeling the praying is very similar to
meditation so my mom will take us to the
church and she will say pray she in
Buddhism we cross a link yeah
in Christian we was we are just little
kid and mom said okay put him like this
then we will put the hint you know then
she would say close your eyes then we
close our eyes then she said think of
everybody in the world
you know they think about everybody in
the world then kid is funny kid will
believe the mom you know then like this
I think everybody then it's difficult
you know then she said pray for
everybody then try then they'd think
about helping everybody they will not
try then sometime we get older you know
kids believe everything they are lucky
when you get older it's a problem see
mom come on
I cannot help everybody in the world
it's not by the way I'm gonna need a
solo say gee if you guys have Oslo okay
I'll give you a few minutes so you know
I was trained by my mom you know at
least think about the homework and try
to help them you know and then when I
got 20 years old I'm like mom it's not
possible it's okay for little kids you
know but when you grow up you know mom
it's not really possible
to change the whole room one person
cannot change the homeroom you know then
you become cynical you know it's not
possible so I'll tell you a story a few
years ago I went to teach in Norway you
met the guy named Christian last year I
think he looks just like Thor I hate
this guy
I hate extremely handsome blond hair
very big muscle you know he's also
family one of the wealthiest family in
Norway so there are three reasons why I
hate him one is here he has her number
too strong number 3 extremely wealthy
the worst thing number 4
he's extremely math so difficult to be
jealous of him
but I still I can do dinner anyway I
went to his country and I taught about
the seats you know then one guy in the
class one young guy he said you know I
always want my have a girlfriend I want
someone to kiss me so I came to your
class now I understand what to do I said
what to do he said there's a famous
restaurant in Oslo many people go there
so tonight I will go to the restaurant I
will kiss every woman in the restaurant
and I will make the seat to find my
girlfriend to kiss me
I said wait wait really does lady also
have many husband okay
this is my friend what should I do
business
I said if you want a partner you need to
plant a seed if you want a plant of
thing you need to find lonely presence
so I said I have different suggestion
okay
you go to the nursing home you find the
old lady and once a week you take her to
the movie she is lonely maybe he doesn't
have family to visit her and you will
plant a scene and then you will meet
your girlfriend so then I came home
about six weeks later I got an email
from him
it works I think the old lady to the
movie and I plant a theme and I got a
girlfriend
I like this systems Tim you guys ready
okay now six months later I got a second
email and there's a video you guys got
the lights ready or you don't need it
you don't need it okay then the video is
about two minutes
the video is in Norway language okay I
don't know what they're talking about
okay they said ccino ccino it has not
yet purchased some attack kar kar Kino
Kino it means a film go to the movie
okay so I will teach you one Norway word
say Chino Chino
so Chino means go to the movie okay now
he sent me this video six months after
he got his girlfriend you tell me what's
the video ready here we go okay play the
video yes Sam you have sound
he is stolen
okay this video play on the television
every week in Norway the video was paid
for by the national telephone company
and the good and the government of
Norway and it says at the end if the
young person take the old person to the
movie the national telephone company and
the government will pay for both tickets
okay now the question is how did this
video start now 100 thousands of young
people are taking hundreds of thousands
of old people to movie every week how
did it start
the boy who decided not to go kiss all
the girls in the restaurants start with
him one person then he he got his
girlfriends then his friend said how you
get five years you don't have girlfriend
no girlfriend
what you do you go plant a seed in the
mercifulness then send that girlfriend
then transferred got girlfriend a
friend's friend thing that govern four
steps virus spread in Norway from one
person so there's two ways to help all
the people in the world you can sit in
the church with your mom I wish I could
help on people's you know you can do
it's a good thing it doesn't help people
directly but indirectly it's very good
indirectly or use the four steps
yourself you become financially
successful you become healthy you know
you get a beautiful relationship happy
marriage
then your family will copy you and a
friends fan will copy you an offense fan
fan then the government will make a
movie probably you will be the star
understand so the best thing you can do
to help everywhere
use the four-step yourself you become
successful yourself then people will
copy you it is possible to help the
whole room each person has a power ok
what do you have to do you because you
have happy marriage you be healthy you
be happy human advertisement understand
cool thank you